<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>S3 on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</title>
    <link>https://www.plakar.io/tags/s3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in S3 on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.plakar.io/tags/s3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technical deep dive into .ptar: replacing .tgz for petabyte-scale S3 archives</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/posts/2025-06-30/technical-deep-dive-into-.ptar-replacing-.tgz-for-petabyte-scale-s3-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/posts/2025-06-30/technical-deep-dive-into-.ptar-replacing-.tgz-for-petabyte-scale-s3-archives/</guid>
      <description>.tgz made sense in 1994, but today we need archiving that supports deduplication, encryption, S3, and zero trust. here’s why we built .ptar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S3</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/s3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-protecting-s3-data-matters&#34;&gt;Why protecting S3 data matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S3 is often treated as the backup, but object storage durability is not the same as data protection. While S3 provides excellent infrastructure resilience, it remains logically vulnerable to:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silent Corruption&lt;/strong&gt;: Data can degrade over time without detection, and standard object storage lacks built-in integrity validation across your entire dataset.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong&gt;: Misconfigured lifecycle policies can automatically delete critical objects. Human errors like bulk delete operations happen instantly and affect thousands of objects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Versioning Gaps&lt;/strong&gt;: Versioning is optional and easy to misconfigure. Even when enabled, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t protect against lifecycle policy deletions or deliberate version purging.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Replication Risks&lt;/strong&gt;: S3 replication is a double-edged sword. It spreads corruption, accidental deletions, and malicious changes just as quickly as legitimate data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For production data, assets, logs, and compliance records, S3 needs an independent safety net beyond buckets and replication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
