<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Plakar integrations on Plakar - Effortless backup</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/integrations/</link><description>Recent content in Plakar integrations on Plakar - Effortless backup</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www-v2.plakar.io/integrations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>S3</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/integrations/s3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/integrations/s3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-s3">What is S3?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>S3 (Simple Storage Service) is a highly available and durable object storage service used to store arbitrary data as discrete objects in buckets. S3 is offered by AWS, and compatible implementations are available via software such as MinIO, Ceph RGW, Wasabi, and Scality Zenko. It is ideal for storing backups, media archives, logs, and large data sets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With Plakar, you can ingest data from S3 buckets into immutable, encrypted snapshots that are verifiable and portable. You can also use S3 as a target repository to store backups created from any source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SFTP</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/integrations/sftp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/integrations/sftp/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="back-up-remote-directories-with-plakar-over-sftp">Back up remote directories with Plakar over SFTP&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>SFTP connector&lt;/strong> allows Plakar to perform secure, encrypted backups of remote files and directories over the SSH File Transfer Protocol (SFTP). This is especially useful for backing up critical infrastructure servers, VPS instances, or remote NAS devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plakar treats an SFTP path as a valid source directory, backing up its contents into any configured Plakar repository. It ensures full snapshot creation, deduplication, and encryption, just as it would for local directories.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>