<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Storage on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/tags/cloud-storage/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Storage on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.plakar.io/tags/cloud-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dropbox</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/dropbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/dropbox/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-dropbox-matters">Why protecting Dropbox matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dropbox is excellent for syncing and sharing files instantly, but syncing is not the same as a backup. Because Dropbox mirrors your actions across all devices, any mistake or error can spread everywhere at once:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Instant Deletion&lt;/strong>: If you or a collaborator accidentally delete a folder, that deletion spreads to every linked computer immediately.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Limited Recovery&lt;/strong>: Dropbox has a specific &amp;ldquo;trash&amp;rdquo; window, but if data loss is discovered after that window closes, those files may be permanently gone.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ransomware&lt;/strong>: If your local files are hit by malware, Dropbox will sync the versions encrypted by malware, overwriting your healthy data in the cloud.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For your important projects and shared team folders, you need an independent record of your data that remains safe, verifiable, and restorable no matter what happens in your live Dropbox environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Drive</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/googledrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/googledrive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-google-drive-matters">Why protecting Google Drive matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Google Drive is central to everyday work and collaboration, but synchronization is not a backup solution. Actions taken in Google Drive are synced to all connected devices almost instantly. This leaves it vulnerable to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong>: Files removed by a user are quickly removed across all devices and shared workspaces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Overwrites and Corruption&lt;/strong>: Bad edits or corrupted files replace healthy versions across the entire environment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ransomware&lt;/strong>: Malware-encrypted files are synchronized back to Google Drive, overwriting clean data.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Native retention and recovery options are limited in scope and duration. For business‑critical or compliance‑sensitive data, an independent and immutable backup history is essential.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Koofr</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/koofr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/koofr/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-koofr-matters">Why protecting Koofr matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Koofr provides privacy-focused cloud storage with multi-cloud integration, but these features are not a backup solution. Actions taken in Koofr can affect your files instantly. This leaves it vulnerable to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong>: Files removed by a user are permanently deleted from your storage.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Overwrites and Corruption&lt;/strong>: Bad edits or corrupted files replace healthy versions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ransomware&lt;/strong>: Malware-encrypted files can overwrite clean data in your Koofr storage.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Native retention and recovery options are limited in scope and duration. For business-critical or compliance-sensitive data, an independent and immutable backup history is essential.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OneDrive</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/onedrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/onedrive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-onedrive-matters">Why protecting OneDrive matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>OneDrive&amp;rsquo;s seamless integration with Microsoft 365 makes it indispensable for modern work, but this same integration creates unique risks. When something goes wrong—whether accidental deletion, file corruption, or ransomware—the problem spreads instantly across every connected device and user. This leaves OneDrive environments vulnerable to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Synchronized Deletions&lt;/strong>: A file deleted on one device disappears from OneDrive and all other devices within seconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rapid Corruption Spread&lt;/strong>: Corrupted or maliciously encrypted files replace healthy versions across your entire organization.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Credential-Based Attacks&lt;/strong>: A single compromised account can be used to delete or encrypt large portions of your shared files.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>While OneDrive provides a recycle bin and version history, these features have time limits and may not protect against determined attackers or cascading failures. For regulated industries or business-critical data, these built-in protections are insufficient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenDrive</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/opendrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/opendrive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-opendrive-matters">Why protecting OpenDrive matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>OpenDrive excels at synchronizing files and making them accessible across devices. But this doesn&amp;rsquo;t count as a backup strategy. Your files are still vulnerable to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong>: Deleted files are synced instantly and may be permanently removed once retention limits are reached.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Overwrites and Corruption&lt;/strong>: Bad edits or corrupted files replace healthy versions across all devices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ransomware&lt;/strong>: Encrypted files created by malware are synced back to OpenDrive, overwriting clean data.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For important personal data, shared folders, or business assets, you need an independent history of your files that cannot be altered by mistakes, malware, or account issues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Proton Drive</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/protondrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/protondrive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-proton-drive-matters">Why protecting Proton Drive matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Proton Drive provides strong privacy through end-to-end encryption, but like any cloud storage platform, it faces risks from accidental deletion, device compromise, and sync propagation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Instant Deletion&lt;/strong>: If you or a collaborator accidentally delete a folder, that deletion spreads to every synced device immediately.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Limited Recovery Window&lt;/strong>: Proton Drive provides a trash retention period, but if data loss is discovered after that window closes, those files may be permanently gone.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ransomware&lt;/strong>: If your local files are encrypted by malware, Proton Drive will sync those corrupted versions, overwriting your healthy data in the cloud.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For important documents and sensitive files, an independent backup provides an additional safety layer that remains available regardless of what happens in your live Proton Drive environment.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>