<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Storage on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/tags/cloud-storage/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Storage on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.plakar.io/tags/cloud-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dropbox</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/dropbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/dropbox/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-dropbox-matters">Why protecting Dropbox matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dropbox is excellent for syncing and sharing files instantly, but syncing is not the same as a backup. Because Dropbox mirrors your actions across all devices, any mistake or error can spread everywhere at once:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Instant Deletion&lt;/strong>: If you or a collaborator accidentally delete a folder, that deletion spreads to every linked computer immediately.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Limited Recovery&lt;/strong>: Dropbox has a specific &amp;ldquo;trash&amp;rdquo; window, but if data loss is discovered after that window closes, those files may be permanently gone.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ransomware&lt;/strong>: If your local files are hit by malware, Dropbox will sync the versions encrypted by malware, overwriting your healthy data in the cloud.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For your important projects and shared team folders, you need an independent record of your data that remains safe, verifiable, and restorable no matter what happens in your live Dropbox environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Drive</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/googledrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/googledrive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-why-protecting-google-drive-matters">🧠 Why protecting Google Drive matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Google Drive is trusted for everyday work and collaboration, but its convenience can mask real risks. Data can be silently corrupted, deleted by mistake, or encrypted by ransomware often with sync propagating the issue instantly across all devices and users. Native retention and recovery options are limited, and compliance needs may go unmet without immutable, verifiable backups.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="-what-happens-when-google-drive-is-compromised-or-data-is-lost">🔓 What happens when Google Drive is compromised or data is lost?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If your Google Drive credentials are leaked, or files are deleted or overwritten whether by accident, malware, or sync error data can vanish instantly across all connected devices. Google’s trash and retention policies offer only short-term protection, and recovery is not guaranteed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Koofr</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/koofr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/koofr/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-why-protecting-koofr-matters">🧠 Why protecting Koofr matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Even privacy-first cloud storage like Koofr is vulnerable to risks beyond its control. Accidental deletions, silent corruption, ransomware, or account lockout can result in permanent data loss. Native versioning and sync features help, but they don’t guarantee recovery from every scenario especially when compliance, audits, or long-term retention are required.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without immutable, externalized backups, your Koofr data remains exposed to operational mistakes and targeted attacks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OneDrive</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/onedrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/onedrive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-why-protecting-onedrive-matters">🧠 Why protecting OneDrive matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cloud sync is not backup. OneDrive’s convenience can mask risks: silent corruption, accidental deletion, ransomware, or compromised credentials can lead to rapid, irreversible data loss. Retention and version history help, but they’re not enough for compliance, audit, or long-term recovery. Without immutable, externalized backups, your files remain vulnerable to threats that propagate faster than you can react.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="-what-happens-when-onedrive-is-compromised">🔓 What happens when OneDrive is compromised?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If files are deleted locally, OneDrive syncs those deletions to the cloud sometimes before you notice. Ransomware or malware can encrypt files and sync the damage across all devices. A breach of your Microsoft account can expose or wipe entire libraries. Native recovery options are limited by retention windows and version history, which may not cover every scenario.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Proton Drive</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/protondrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/protondrive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-why-protecting-proton-drive-matters">🧠 Why protecting Proton Drive matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cloud sync and encryption protect privacy, but not against all risks. Files in Proton Drive can be lost to accidental deletion, overwritten by malware, or permanently removed after trash expiry. Account lockouts or credential loss can make data inaccessible, and compliance needs often require more than basic retention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without immutable backups, recovery from these scenarios is unreliable or impossible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="-what-happens-when-proton-drive-files-are-deleted-or-compromised">🔓 What happens when Proton Drive files are deleted or compromised?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If files are deleted intentionally or by mistake across synced devices, or if ransomware overwrites originals, Proton Drive’s native features may not help. Trash expiry or account suspension can make recovery impossible, and sync can propagate errors instantly.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>