<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Minio on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</title>
    <link>https://www.plakar.io/tags/minio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Minio on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.plakar.io/tags/minio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MinIO integration</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/docs/v1.0.5/integrations/minio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/docs/v1.0.5/integrations/minio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This documentation assumes Plakar v1.0.4 or superior is installed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plakar&amp;rsquo;s MinIO integration includes three connectors:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage connector&lt;/strong&gt;: to host a Kloset store in a MinIO bucket.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source connector&lt;/strong&gt;: to back up any MinIO bucket into an existing Kloset store.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Destination connector&lt;/strong&gt;: to restore from any Kloset store into a MinIO bucket.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use-cases for this integration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host a Kloset store in a MinIO bucket&lt;/strong&gt;, and use it to back up your local filesystem, remote servers, databases, or any other data source supported by Plakar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backup a MinIO bucket&lt;/strong&gt; to any Kloset store, for example hosted on the local filesystem, in a remote SFTP server, or even in another MinIO bucket.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restore a snapshot from a Kloset store into a MinIO bucket&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compatibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S3</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/s3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-protecting-s3-data-matters&#34;&gt;Why protecting S3 data matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S3 is often treated as the backup, but object storage durability is not the same as data protection. While S3 provides excellent infrastructure resilience, it remains logically vulnerable to:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silent Corruption&lt;/strong&gt;: Data can degrade over time without detection, and standard object storage lacks built-in integrity validation across your entire dataset.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong&gt;: Misconfigured lifecycle policies can automatically delete critical objects. Human errors like bulk delete operations happen instantly and affect thousands of objects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Versioning Gaps&lt;/strong&gt;: Versioning is optional and easy to misconfigure. Even when enabled, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t protect against lifecycle policy deletions or deliberate version purging.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Replication Risks&lt;/strong&gt;: S3 replication is a double-edged sword. It spreads corruption, accidental deletions, and malicious changes just as quickly as legitimate data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For production data, assets, logs, and compliance records, S3 needs an independent safety net beyond buckets and replication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
