<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Viewer on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</title>
    <link>https://www.plakar.io/categories/viewer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Viewer on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.plakar.io/categories/viewer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SFTP</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/sftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/sftp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-protecting-sftp-matters&#34;&gt;Why protecting SFTP matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SFTP is a standard for secure file transfers across Linux servers, BSD hosts, and NAS devices like Synology and QNAP. However, secure transfer is not the same as a backup strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While SFTP secures the data in transit, it does not protect the data once it arrives to where you want to store it. Standard SFTP setups face several risks:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of Versioning&lt;/strong&gt;: Files can be overwritten or deleted immediately after upload.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Immutability&lt;/strong&gt;: There are no permanent snapshots to revert to if a file is corrupted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational Risk&lt;/strong&gt;: Manual transfers or custom scripts are error-prone and difficult to audit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When compliance, uptime, or disaster recovery is critical, simply storing files on SFTP is not enough. You need verifiable, immutable backups that can survive mistakes, misconfigurations, or attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iCloud Drive</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/iclouddrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/iclouddrive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-protecting-icloud-drive-matters&#34;&gt;Why protecting iCloud Drive matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;iCloud Drive is central to the Apple ecosystem, seamlessly syncing files across devices, however synchronization doesn&amp;rsquo;t count as a backup solution. Actions taken in iCloud Drive are synced to all connected devices almost instantly. This leaves it vulnerable to:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong&gt;: Files removed by a user are quickly removed across all devices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overwrites and Corruption&lt;/strong&gt;: Bad edits or corrupted files replace healthy versions across the entire environment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ransomware&lt;/strong&gt;: Malware-encrypted files are synchronized back to iCloud Drive, overwriting clean data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Native retention and recovery options are limited in scope and duration. While Apple provides some version history, it&amp;rsquo;s restricted to recent changes and specific file types. For business-critical or compliance-sensitive data, an independent and immutable backup history is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MinIO</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/minio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/minio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-protecting-minio-matters&#34;&gt;Why protecting MinIO matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Object storage is often perceived as durable by default, but durability is not the same as a backup. Many organizations use MinIO to store logs, datasets, container images, or even other backup files, assuming they are safe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, without independent immutability and integrity validation, data stored in MinIO is still vulnerable to:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silent Corruption&lt;/strong&gt;: Data can degrade over time without being noticed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong&gt;: Misconfigured lifecycle policies can delete important data automatically.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access Mismanagement&lt;/strong&gt;: If security keys are leaked or misused, your entire data store can be wiped or altered.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When retention and recovery are mission-critical, simply storing objects is not enough. You need a verifiable backup strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filesystem</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/fs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/fs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-protecting-your-filesystem-matters&#34;&gt;Why protecting your Filesystem matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of us protect our files by simply copying them to an external drive or a USB stick. While having a second copy is a good start, it isn&amp;rsquo;t a real backup strategy. Standard file copying leaves your data vulnerable to a few common problems:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong&gt;: If you delete a file by mistake and your sync tool mirrors that change, the file is gone from both places.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ransomware and Corruption&lt;/strong&gt;: If your files are hit by malware or a disk failure, &amp;ldquo;copying&amp;rdquo; those files usually just preserves the damaged versions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human Error&lt;/strong&gt;: It is incredibly easy to overwrite a new version of a document with an old one during a manual move.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For your personal photos, system settings, or work projects, you need a way to go back to a specific version of your data that you know is safe and healthy in case of a mishap with your current data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FTP</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/ftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/ftp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-protecting-ftp-servers-matters&#34;&gt;Why protecting FTP servers matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FTP is a standard protocol for file transfers across public repositories, network appliances, and production systems. However, file transfer is not the same as a backup strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While FTP moves files between systems, it does not protect the data once it arrives. Standard FTP setups face several risks:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of Versioning&lt;/strong&gt;: Files can be overwritten or deleted immediately after upload.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Immutability&lt;/strong&gt;: There are no permanent snapshots to revert to if a file is corrupted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational Risk&lt;/strong&gt;: Manual transfers or custom scripts are error-prone and difficult to audit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply storing files via FTP is not enough when compliance, uptime, or disaster recovery is critical. You need verifiable, immutable backups that can survive mistakes, misconfigurations, or unauthorized access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S3</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/s3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-protecting-s3-data-matters&#34;&gt;Why protecting S3 data matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S3 is often treated as the backup, but object storage durability is not the same as data protection. While S3 provides excellent infrastructure resilience, it remains logically vulnerable to:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silent Corruption&lt;/strong&gt;: Data can degrade over time without detection, and standard object storage lacks built-in integrity validation across your entire dataset.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong&gt;: Misconfigured lifecycle policies can automatically delete critical objects. Human errors like bulk delete operations happen instantly and affect thousands of objects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Versioning Gaps&lt;/strong&gt;: Versioning is optional and easy to misconfigure. Even when enabled, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t protect against lifecycle policy deletions or deliberate version purging.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Replication Risks&lt;/strong&gt;: S3 replication is a double-edged sword. It spreads corruption, accidental deletions, and malicious changes just as quickly as legitimate data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For production data, assets, logs, and compliance records, S3 needs an independent safety net beyond buckets and replication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tar</title>
      <link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/tar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/tar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-tar-archives-with-plakar&#34;&gt;Using tar archives with Plakar&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tar has been a standard Unix archive format for decades, commonly used to bundle files for distribution, transfer, and simple backups. It is widely supported and highly portable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tar archives themselves do not provide backup semantics such as deduplication, version tracking, or built-in encryption. Managing backups as collections of independent tar files becomes difficult as data evolves over time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tar archives are imported into Plakar, which handles storage, deduplication, and verification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
