<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Viewer on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/categories/viewer/</link><description>Recent content in Viewer on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.plakar.io/categories/viewer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SFTP</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/sftp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/sftp/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-sftp-matters">Why protecting SFTP matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SFTP is a standard for secure file transfers across Linux servers, BSD hosts, and NAS devices like Synology and QNAP. However, secure transfer is not the same as a backup strategy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While SFTP secures the data in transit, it does not protect the data once it arrives to where you want to store it. Standard SFTP setups face several risks:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lack of Versioning&lt;/strong>: Files can be overwritten or deleted immediately after upload.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>No Immutability&lt;/strong>: There are no permanent snapshots to revert to if a file is corrupted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Operational Risk&lt;/strong>: Manual transfers or custom scripts are error-prone and difficult to audit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When compliance, uptime, or disaster recovery is critical, simply storing files on SFTP is not enough. You need verifiable, immutable backups that can survive mistakes, misconfigurations, or attacks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iCloud Drive</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/iclouddrive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/iclouddrive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-why-protecting-icloud-drive-matters">🧠 Why protecting iCloud Drive matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>iCloud Drive syncs files across all your Apple devices, but sync is not backup. If files are deleted, corrupted, or compromised, those changes propagate everywhere instantly. Without immutable backups, you risk silent data loss, ransomware spread, or compliance failures, and recovery options are limited or unavailable.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="-what-happens-when-icloud-drive-files-are-deleted-or-compromised">🔓 What happens when iCloud Drive files are deleted or compromised?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A mistaken deletion, malware infection, or stolen credentials can wipe or corrupt your files across every device. Native versioning is limited and often hidden, making recovery unreliable. If you need to restore a specific version or recover from a major incident, iCloud Drive alone cannot guarantee data integrity or rollback.
Icloud can be backed up by Apple but it is not free and after 180 days it is deleted, and it does not provide the level of control and security that Plakar offers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MinIO</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/minio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/minio/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-minio-matters">Why protecting MinIO matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Object storage is often perceived as durable by default, but durability is not the same as a backup. Many organizations use MinIO to store logs, datasets, container images, or even other backup files, assuming they are safe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, without independent immutability and integrity validation, data stored in MinIO is still vulnerable to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Silent Corruption&lt;/strong>: Data can degrade over time without being noticed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong>: Misconfigured lifecycle policies can delete important data automatically.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Access Mismanagement&lt;/strong>: If security keys are leaked or misused, your entire data store can be wiped or altered.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When retention and recovery are mission-critical, simply storing objects is not enough. You need a verifiable backup strategy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Filesystem</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/fs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/fs/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-your-filesystem-matters">Why protecting your Filesystem matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Most of us protect our files by simply copying them to an external drive or a USB stick. While having a second copy is a good start, it isn&amp;rsquo;t a real backup strategy. Standard file copying leaves your data vulnerable to a few common problems:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong>: If you delete a file by mistake and your sync tool mirrors that change, the file is gone from both places.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ransomware and Corruption&lt;/strong>: If your files are hit by malware or a disk failure, &amp;ldquo;copying&amp;rdquo; those files usually just preserves the damaged versions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Human Error&lt;/strong>: It is incredibly easy to overwrite a new version of a document with an old one during a manual move.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For your personal photos, system settings, or work projects, you need a way to go back to a specific version of your data that you know is safe and healthy in case of a mishap with your current data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FTP</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/ftp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/ftp/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="ftp-integration">FTP Integration&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>FTP integration&lt;/strong> provides support for the legacy, though still around, FTP protocol.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It can either backup from a public FTP server or restore to an authentication-less FTP server, a local NAS for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configuration">Configuration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>FTP integration&lt;/strong> does not require any particular configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="example-usage">Example Usage&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To back up the path &lt;code>/pub/PlakarKorp&lt;/code> from FTP server located at &lt;code>example.org&lt;/code>, you can use the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-sh" data-lang="sh">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">$ plakar at /var/backups backup ftp://example.org/pub/PlakarKorp
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>To restore data to authentication-less FTP server located at &lt;code>example.org&lt;/code>, use the following command:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>S3</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/s3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/s3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-why-protecting-s3-data-matters">🧠 Why protecting S3 data matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>S3 is often treated as the backup, but object storage is not immune to failure or abuse:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Objects can be overwritten or deleted instantly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Versioning is optional and easy to misconfigure&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Replication spreads corruption just as fast as good data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lifecycle policies can silently delete critical objects&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In practice, S3 is highly durable but logically fragile.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Human error, compromised credentials, buggy applications, or ransomware can destroy or encrypt entire buckets in seconds.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tar</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/tar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/tar/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="using-tar-archives-with-plakar">Using tar archives with Plakar&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Tar has been a standard Unix archive format for decades, commonly used to bundle files for distribution, transfer, and simple backups. It is widely supported and highly portable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tar archives themselves do not provide backup semantics such as deduplication, version tracking, or built-in encryption. Managing backups as collections of independent tar files becomes difficult as data evolves over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tar archives are imported into Plakar, which handles storage, deduplication, and verification.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>