<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data protection stories on Plakar - Effortless backup</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Data protection stories on Plakar - Effortless backup</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Short history of backup</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/2025-03-31-a_short_history_of_backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/2025-03-31-a_short_history_of_backup/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="in-honor-of-world-backup-day--march-31">In honor of World Backup Day – March 31&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Plakar 1.0.1-beta.13 out !</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/2025-03_02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/2025-03_02/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, it&amp;rsquo;s me again !&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We released our first beta late February but we weren’t just going to sit back and stay idle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m glad to announce that we have just released &lt;code>v1.0.1-beta.13&lt;/code>,
our latest version of &lt;code>plakar&lt;/code>,
incorporating several new features and solving some of the bugs reported by early adopters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Plakar beta.4 and upcoming features</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/2025-03_01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/2025-03_01/</guid><description>&lt;p>We were thrilled to release our first beta in late February,
but we weren’t just going to sit back and rest on our laurels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead,
we immediately set our sights on refining our product,
incorporating valuable user feedback,
and developing innovative features that would take our software to the next level.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Want to stay updated ?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Star&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Watch&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Follow @PlakarKorp&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Plakar beta release !</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/2025-02_01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/2025-02_01/</guid><description>&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Listen to this article as an AI-generated podcast as you read !&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Hello!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The past few months have been incredibly intense as we launched Plakar Korp to support the development of &lt;code>plakar&lt;/code> and other related software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In just one quarter,
I transitioned from working solo to collaborating with a highly talented team—all of whom I had worked with before in various contexts and knew would be a perfect fit.
Not only did they catch up remarkably fast on the existing codebase,
but each of them also introduced very significant improvements, which is simply astounding to me!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding RTO and RPO in disaster recovery</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/understanding-rto-and-rpo-in-disaster-recovery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 02:11:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/understanding-rto-and-rpo-in-disaster-recovery/</guid><description>&lt;p>In today’s digital landscape, where &lt;strong>downtime can cost businesses thousands of dollars per minute&lt;/strong>, having a robust &lt;strong>disaster recovery (DR) strategy&lt;/strong> is non-negotiable. Two fundamental metrics in any &lt;strong>business continuity plan&lt;/strong> are &lt;strong>recovery time objective (RTO)&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>recovery point objective (RPO)&lt;/strong>. These determine how quickly a system can recover after a failure and how much data a company is willing to lose in the process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>S3 is not a backup: why you need a real backup strategy</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/s3-is-not-a-backup---why-you-need-a-real-backup-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 15:12:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/s3-is-not-a-backup---why-you-need-a-real-backup-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let us get straight to the point: Amazon S3 is a phenomenal service for scalable, reliable object storage but it is not a backup solution. Sure, S3 boasts rock-solid durability and cost efficiency, but relying on it alone for backups is like trying to cover your bases with duct tape. In today’s world, where a single misclick can spell disaster, a thoughtful, multi-layered backup strategy is not just nice to have; it is absolutely essential.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why replication is not backup</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/why-replication-is-not-backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 15:02:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/why-replication-is-not-backup/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the realm of data protection, &lt;strong>backup&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>replication&lt;/strong> are two fundamental strategies employed to safeguard information. While they share the common goal of data preservation, they operate on distinct principles and serve different purposes. Understanding these differences is crucial for developing a robust data protection strategy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The 3-2-1 backup rule: A proven strategy for data protection</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/the-3-2-1-backup-rule---a-proven-strategy-for-data-protection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:24:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/the-3-2-1-backup-rule---a-proven-strategy-for-data-protection/</guid><description>&lt;p>Data loss can happen in many ways: whether due to accidental deletion, cyberattacks, hardware failure, or even a catastrophic event like a &lt;strong>data center fire&lt;/strong>. To protect against these risks, IT professionals have long relied on the &lt;strong>3-2-1 backup rule&lt;/strong>, a fundamental strategy for ensuring data resilience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Test placeholder</title><link>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/post-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www-v2.plakar.io/posts/post-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello from my post!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>