<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on Plakar | The Open Standard for Backup and Restore</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.plakar.io/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notion</title><link>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/notion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.plakar.io/integrations/notion/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-protecting-notion-matters">Why protecting Notion matters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Notion has become central to how organizations document processes, manage projects, and preserve institutional knowledge. As more critical information moves into Notion, the risks of data loss grow proportionally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notion provides platform availability and collaboration features, but it does not guarantee recovery from common failure scenarios. Standard Notion usage faces several risks:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Accidental Deletion&lt;/strong>: Pages and databases can be permanently deleted by any user with edit access.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Unauthorized Changes&lt;/strong>: API integrations, compromised accounts, or malicious actors can modify or destroy content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Limited Version History&lt;/strong>: Notion&amp;rsquo;s native version history has retention limits and cannot protect against all scenarios.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Export Limitations&lt;/strong>: Native exports are one-time snapshots in generic formats that lose structure and relationships.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="security-and-compromise">Security and Compromise&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Notion workspaces are accessed via user accounts, API tokens, and third-party integrations. If credentials are compromised or permissions are misconfigured, your workspace is vulnerable:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>